<?xml version="1.0"?>
<metadata xml:lang="en"><Esri><CreaDate>20240827</CreaDate><CreaTime>11263700</CreaTime><ArcGISFormat>1.0</ArcGISFormat><SyncOnce>TRUE</SyncOnce><ModDate>20250825</ModDate><ModTime>15255900</ModTime><scaleRange><minScale>150000000</minScale><maxScale>5000</maxScale></scaleRange><ArcGISProfile>ISO19115_3</ArcGISProfile></Esri><tool name="aggregator" displayname="Summarize Soil Information" toolboxalias="Soil Data Development Toolbox" xmlns=""><arcToolboxHelpPath>c:\program files\arcgis\pro\Resources\Help\gp</arcToolboxHelpPath><parameters><param name="inputSSURGO" displayname="gSSURGO Feature or Raster" type="Optional" direction="Input" datatype="String" expression="{Map Unit Polygons - DC [map: 0] | MURASTER_10m [map: 1]}"><dialogReference>&lt;DIV STYLE="text-align:Left;"&gt;&lt;DIV&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;For the moment this optional parameter is for convenience in selecting a gSSURGO dataset from your map table of contents.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Eventually this parameter will be used to join the summary table to and map produced.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;/DIV&gt;</dialogReference></param><param name="inputFolder" displayname="gSSURGO Database" type="Required" direction="Input" datatype="Workspace" expression="inputFolder"><dialogReference>&lt;DIV STYLE="text-align:Left;"&gt;&lt;DIV&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Specify the gSSURGO file geodatabase. The soil property or interpretation will summarized from this dataset and the summary table will be written to this gSSURGO database.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;/DIV&gt;</dialogReference></param><param name="filters" displayname="Choice List Filters" type="Optional" direction="Input" datatype="String" expression="{By Table}"><dialogReference>&lt;DIV STYLE="text-align:Left;"&gt;&lt;DIV&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;There are hundreds of different soil properties and interpretations that can be summarized from a gSSURGO dataset. The "By Table" option allows you to browse specify any field an available SSURGO table. This option requires some understanding of the data structure. Soil Data Viewer Categories is a list of popular categories of data. Soil Data Viewer List is the complete list of popular soil properties and interpretations.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;/DIV&gt;</dialogReference></param><param name="SDVcat1" displayname="SDV Category" type="Optional" direction="Input" datatype="String" expression="{SDVcat1}"><dialogReference>&lt;DIV STYLE="text-align:Left;"&gt;&lt;DIV&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Select a top level category of soil properties and interpretations. Once a category is selected you will be presented with a curated list soil properties and interpretations.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;/DIV&gt;</dialogReference></param><param name="tables" displayname="Primary Table" type="Optional" direction="Input" datatype="String" expression="{Component | Horizon | Interpretations | Component Crop Yield: Irrigated | Component Crop Yield: Nonirrigated}"><dialogReference>&lt;DIV STYLE="text-align:Left;"&gt;&lt;DIV&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Select a SSURGO table with the soil properties and interpretation you are looking for. &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Component level tables contain information that describes the whole soil, such as drainage, taxonomy, site information, etc.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Horizon level tables contain information about the unique soil horizons, such as clay content, pH, etc. &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Interpretations convey information about how suitable or limiting a soil type might be for certain activities or uses, such as buildings with basements or supporting Long Leaf Pines. These interpretations are pre-calculated at the component level but must be summarized to the map unit level. &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;/DIV&gt;</dialogReference></param><param name="attribute" displayname="Primary Soil Attribute (select one)" type="Optional" direction="Input" datatype="Multiple Value" expression="{attribute;attribute...}"><dialogReference>&lt;DIV STYLE="text-align:Left;"&gt;&lt;DIV&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Specify a single soil property of interpretation to be summarized. &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Note that you can search terms using the top drop down &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt; &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;/DIV&gt;</dialogReference></param><param name="primary" displayname="Primary Constraint" type="Optional" direction="Input" datatype="Multiple Value" expression="{primary;primary...}"><dialogReference>&lt;DIV STYLE="text-align:Left;"&gt;&lt;DIV&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;This option is made available when summarizing Percent Present of nominal classes, such as Taxonomic Order, for example if you want to summarize how much of a map unit is of the soil order "Histisols".&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;It is also an option presented when selecting a crop when summarizing Component Crop Yield.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;/DIV&gt;</dialogReference></param><param name="agmeth" displayname="Aggregation Method" type="Optional" direction="Input" datatype="String" expression="{agmeth}"><dialogReference>&lt;DIV STYLE="text-align:Left;"&gt;&lt;DIV&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;Aggregation Method is the process by which the soil property or interpretation is reduced to a single value that represents the map unit as a whole. A map unit is typically composed of one or more "components". A component is either some type of soil or some nonsoil entity, e.g., rock outcrop. For the attribute being aggregated, the first step of the aggregation process is to derive one attribute value for each of a map unit's components. From this set of component attributes, the next step of the aggregation process derives a single value that represents the map unit as a whole. Once a single value for each map unit is derived, a thematic map for soil map units can be rendered. Aggregation must be done because, on any soil map, map units are delineated but components are not. For each of a map unit's components, a corresponding percent composition is recorded. A percent composition of 60 indicates that the corresponding component typically makes up approximately 60% of the map unit. Percent composition is a critical factor in some, but not all, aggregation methods.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN STYLE="font-weight:bold;"&gt;Dominant Condition&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;: Available for categorical properties and interpretations. This aggregation method presents the most prevalent condition. It first groups components with the same class and sums the percent composition to determine the "dominant condition of a map unit. These groups now represent "conditions" rather than components. The attribute value associated with the group with the highest cumulative percent composition is returned. If more than one group shares the highest cumulative percent composition, the corresponding "tie-break" rule determines which value should be returned. The result returned by this aggregation method represents the dominant condition throughout the map unit only when no tie has occurred.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN STYLE="font-weight:bold;"&gt;Dominant Component&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;: Available for all properties and interpretations. This method returns the attribute value associated with the component with the highest percent composition in the map unit. The result returned by this aggregation method may or may not represent the dominant condition throughout the map unit. There is only one dominant component per map unit.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN STYLE="font-weight:bold;"&gt;Weighted Average&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;: Available for continuous soil properties and to acquire the weighted average of interpretation fuzzy values. Computes a weighted average value for all components in the map unit. Percent composition is the weighting factor. The result returned by this aggregation method represents a weighted average value of the corresponding attribute throughout the map unit.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN STYLE="font-weight:bold;"&gt;Minimum&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;: Available for continuous soil properties. The lowest attribute value among all components of the map unit. The result may correspond to a map unit component of very minor extent. This aggregation method is appropriate for either numeric attributes or attributes with a ranked or logically ordered domain.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;LI&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN STYLE="font-weight:bold;"&gt;Maximum&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;: Available for continuous soil properties. The highest attribute value among all components of the map unit. The result may correspond to a map unit component of very minor extent. This aggregation method is appropriate for either numeric attributes or attributes with a ranked or logically ordered domain.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;/DIV&gt;</dialogReference></param><param name="stables" displayname="Secondary Table" type="Optional" direction="Input" datatype="String" expression="{stables}"/><param name="sattribute" displayname="Secondary Soil Attribute" type="Optional" direction="Input" datatype="String" expression="{sattribute}"/><param name="secondary" displayname="Secondary Constraint" type="Optional" direction="Input" datatype="Multiple Value" expression="{secondary;secondary...}"/><param name="depths" displayname="Depth Ranges (cm)" type="Optional" direction="Input" datatype="Value Table" expression="{Top {Bottom};Top {Bottom}...}"/><param name="month1" displayname="Timespan" type="Optional" direction="Input" datatype="Value Table" expression="{Beginning {End};Beginning {End}...}"/><param name="tie" displayname="Tie Break Rule" type="Optional" direction="Input" datatype="String" expression="{Higher | Lower}"><dialogReference>&lt;DIV STYLE="text-align:Left;"&gt;&lt;DIV&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;The "tie-break" rule indicates whether the lower or higher group value should be returned in the case of a percent composition tie. &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;/DIV&gt;</dialogReference></param><param name="comp_pct" displayname="Component Percent Cutoff" type="Required" direction="Input" datatype="Long" expression="comp_pct"/><param name="range_value" displayname="Property Range Value" type="Optional" direction="Input" datatype="String" expression="{Representative | Low | High}"/><param name="fuzzy" displayname="Map Interp Fuzzy Values" type="Optional" direction="Input" datatype="Boolean" expression="{fuzzy}"/><param name="rating_null" displayname="Include Null Rating Values" type="Optional" direction="Input" datatype="Boolean" expression="{rating_null}"/><param name="null" displayname="Treat Null entries as Zero" type="Optional" direction="Input" datatype="Boolean" expression="{null}"/><param name="major" displayname="Only consider Major components" type="Optional" direction="Input" datatype="Boolean" expression="{major}"/><param name="primaryNOT" displayname="Invert Primary Constraint to NOT equal" type="Optional" direction="Input" datatype="Boolean" expression="{primaryNOT}"/><param name="secondaryNOT" displayname="Invert Secondary Constraint to NOT equal" type="Optional" direction="Input" datatype="Boolean" expression="{secondaryNOT}"/></parameters><summary>&lt;DIV STYLE="text-align:Left;"&gt;&lt;DIV&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN STYLE="font-size:14pt"&gt;The purpose of this tool is to aggregate soils information to the map unit level ( by mukey). Once soil information is aggregated to the map unit level it can be joined to MUPOLYGON and used to map the summarized property.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P STYLE="font-size:16ptmargin:7 0 7 0;"&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;This tool is not compatible with SSURGO shapefiles because the associated attribute tables are in a different workspace.&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN /&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;/DIV&gt;</summary></tool><dataIdInfo><idCitation><resTitle>Summarize Soil Information</resTitle></idCitation><searchKeys><keyword>Create Soil Map</keyword><keyword>Aggregation</keyword></searchKeys></dataIdInfo><distInfo><distributor><distorFormat><formatName>ArcToolbox Tool</formatName></distorFormat></distributor></distInfo><mdHrLv><ScopeCd value="005"></ScopeCd></mdHrLv><mdDateSt Sync="TRUE">20250825</mdDateSt></metadata>
